rbfcu.org 2012-10-11

# RBFCU: Privacy Policy

At RBFCU, we take the privacy and security of your information very seriously. We've put security measures in place to protect your information, and we are judicious when it comes to sharing your information.

Please review our privacy policy to learn more about the ways in which your information may be shared. If you have questions or comments regarding our privacy policy, you may contact us by e-mail at [comments@rbfcu.org](mailto:comments@rbfcu.org) or may call our Member Service Center at 210-945-3300 (San Antonio), 512-833-3300 (Austin), or 1-800-580-3300 (toll-free).

## Privacy Concerns of Our Members

Your privacy and security concerning your personal affairs is of the utmost importance to us. We have implemented standards and procedures designed to prevent the misuse of the nonpublic personal information you have entrusted to us. These standards and procedures are based on applicable federal laws and Texas state statutes that will govern how we handle your account with us. Our Privacy Policy listed below explains what information Randolph-Brooks Federal Credit Union (RBFCU) and our affiliates collect, when we share it, and how we protect it.

Understanding how important personal privacy is to you when you visit our website, we have adopted the following Online Privacy Policy, in order to better serve you, our valued member.

## Collection and Retention of Member Information when Using NetBranch

We will automatically collect information from "cookies", which are electronic files that capture information about you when you access our online services. Examples are the date and time of your visit, the Internet provider address you were assigned, and the pages you access on our website. If you participate in any surveys and/or site registrations, we will retain that information as well. The information we obtain from you will remain strictly confidential, as we do not disclose cookie information to non-affiliated third parties or affiliates. Examples of how member information may be used include, but are not limited to:

  1. To improve our website;
  2. To notify you about updates or enhancements to our website;
  3. To contact you for special promotions; or
  4. To keep you informed of developments in the Credit Union Movement

While most web browsers automatically accept "cookies", users are capable of preventing their web browser from using the cookies stored in their personal computer's hard drive. Since cookies are required to maintain a secure Internet connection between you and our website, please be aware that if you disable cookies, or these small files of information from being deposited on your computer, you may encounter difficulty using certain features of our website.

## E-Mail Security

If you choose to provide us with your e-mail address, it will be used in the manner specified by you. This information will not be sold to third parties. If you authorize it, we will provide your e-mail address to a third party vendor we hire to provide services to you. If at any time you wish to change your preference regarding how your e-mail is used, you may contact us using the [memberservices@rbfcu.org](mailto:memberservices@rbfcu.org) online address.

E-mail sent to RBFCU may be used by the credit union's staff and volunteers to answer questions, to follow up on suggestions, or to improve the level of service RBFCU provides. However, users are advised that e-mail may not be secured and is subject to interception by unauthorized individuals. Therefore, if you wish to communicate sensitive or personal information, we ask that you send it by traditional postal mail or through a secure message originated on NetBranch Online. Should you choose to request sensitive or confidential information from us via unsecured Internet e-mail, we can not be responsible for your information or any liability associated there of. Users accept full liability for the risks associated with either their messages or our responses being intercepted or altered by unauthorized third parties.

## Our Security Procedures to Protect Information

To help prevent unauthorized access to your nonpublic personal information, we uphold the security standards detailed in this Privacy Policy and the NetBranch Online User Agreement for all online transactions.

Our website only supports web browsers having a Secured Sockets Layer (SSL) 128-bit encryption level.

## Consent

We utilize state of the art systems to monitor users who are connected to our web site or NetBranch Online. All network traffic on our system is constantly monitored for security, copyright, and statistical purposes. By accessing our website, users consent to security testing and monitoring necessary to improve the protection of information and its integrity. Unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, to download this entire website, or otherwise cause damage are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and any other applicable local, state, federal and/or international laws.

## Privacy Notice

Randolph-Brooks Federal Credit Union respects your right to privacy. We adhere to procedures that protect your personal financial information. It is of the utmost importance to safeguard your privacy and preserve your trust in us. We are owned by our membership and governed by a volunteer Board of Directors elected by our members. We are required by law to give you this privacy notice to explain how we collect, use, and safeguard your personal financial information. This notice is provided on behalf of Randolph-Brooks and, when required, by our affiliates: Randolph Brooks Services Group, LLC; Randolph Brooks Title Company, LLC; Randolph Brooks Insurance Agency, LLC; CU Realty of Texas, LLC; and Member Business Lending, LLC. If you have any questions, please contact a representative in our Member Service Center at 210-945-3300 (San Antonio), 512-833-3300 (Austin), or 1-800-580-3300 (toll-free).

## How We Protect Your Information

Our employees are trained in the importance of maintaining confidentiality and member privacy. We restrict access to nonpublic personal information about you to those employees who have a specific business purpose in using your data. We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations and industry practices to protect your nonpublic personal information.

## Information We Collect and Disclose About You

We are committed to providing competitive products and services to meet your financial needs, which necessitates that we share information about you to complete your transactions and to provide certain financial opportunities. In order to do so, we may share some information, excluding information collected from consumer reporting agencies, with our affiliates. Our affiliates provide a variety of financial services such as retirement planning, insurance products and services, real estate title insurance and closing services, real estate brokerage services, and Small Business Administration loans.

We reserve the right to disclose information noted above to any new affiliates of Randolph-Brooks Federal Credit Union and to other companies that provide services to us or additional financial products for your consideration. We also share information with non-affiliated companies that provide products and services on our behalf such as marketing, data processing, and online bill payment. To protect our members' privacy, we only work with companies that consent to strong confidentiality agreements that limit use of the information we provide to a specific purpose. As part of the confidentiality agreements, we do not permit these companies to sell the information we provide them to other third parties.

We collect the following nonpublic personal information about you from a variety of sources and may disclose all the information we collect, except information collected from consumer reporting agencies, to our affiliates.

From membership and loan applications and other forms, we obtain information you provide such as name, address, Social Security Number, and income.

From your transactions with us, our affiliates, or other third party companies that work closely with us to provide you with financial products and services, we obtain information such as your account balances, payment history, parties involved in transactions, and credit card usage.

From consumer reporting agencies, we obtain information such as your creditworthiness and credit history.

From verifications of information you provide on applications and other forms, we obtain information from current or past employers, other financial institutions, and other sources listed on the application. We may also disclose information we collect about you under other circumstances as permitted or required by law. These disclosures typically include information to process transactions on your behalf, conduct the operations of our credit union, follow your instructions as you authorize, or protect the security of our financial records.

If you terminate your membership with us, we will not share information we have collected about you, except as permitted or required by law.

_Since 1952, we have worked hard to protect your privacy, we will never sell your information to others. Our members are part of our family and we take care of family._

This credit union is federally insured by the National Credit Union Administration.

## We Respect Your Privacy

As an added service to our members, we would like to make you aware that the national credit reporting bureaus offer a toll-free number to enable consumers to opt-out of all pre-approved credit offers just by making one telephone call. If you would like to restrict these third parties from obtaining your information from consumer reporting agencies and using for marketing purposes, please call 1-888-5-OPTOUT (1-888-567-8688).

## Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We will revise our Privacy Policy from time to time without notice; however, all significant changes will be posted to this website. As a result, we encourage you to periodically check this web page for changes when accessing our website. NO PROVISIONS CONTAINED HEREIN SHALL BE DETERMINED TO CHANGE OR ALTER ANY OTHER CONTRACTS OR POLICIES BETWEEN RANDOLPH-BROOKS FEDERAL CREDIT UNION AND ITS MEMBERS.

## Contact the Randolph-Brooks Family

We welcome any questions or comments you may have concerning our Privacy Policy. You may contact us by e-mail at [memberservices@rbfcu.org](mailto:memberservices@rbfcu.org), or by calling our Member Service Center at 210-945-3300 (San Antonio), 512-833-3300 (Austin), or 1-800-580-3300 (toll-free).
